# Resumé - UI/UX & Graphic Designer | Peter Koenders

I'm a versatile UI/UX designer with over 20 years of all-round industry experience. I am originally from a traditional Graphic Design background and transitioned into Digital and Web Design. I have worked with small and large organisations. I am fastidious in work flow; definition and planning, research, design, technical, management and review.

- Implementation of the UI/UX design process
- · Estimating & proposal review
- · Iterative wire-framing, prototypes & design
- · Building, maintaining design systems
- · HTML templates & components
- · Graphic design

I take an interest in and am an advocate for digital accessibility. I am also am curious and enjoy working with creative teams on diversified digital projects.

With professionalism, integrity and care, I work in a collaborative manner to plan, design and deliver crafted solutions with best practices in mind.



pkoenders@gmail.com



+64 2115 51085



https://pkoenders.netlify.app



https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-koenders



Westend, Palmerston North, 4410, New Zealand

# **Experiences**

# **Contractor - Designer**

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

#### My Life My Voice

Working as a designer/developer for MLMV, I built a multilingual and accessible JAMstack website and progressive web app. I used Gatsby as the HTML/JS framework and used Sanity as a headless CMS.

#### Responsibilities

#### Design

Design of web pages, journeys, components ensuring Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1 are adhered to.

#### **Development**

Used the JAMstack framework to build a serverless and Progressive Web App to deliver a locale multilingual experience (English, Māori + other) for users. Implemented the Sanity API to source content via GraphQL.

#### **Contractor & Volunteer** Jun 2019 - Aug 2020

#### Sustainable Solutions, Muscular Dystrophy Association & Lynn Pronk

I have taken on contract and volunteer work on range of projects as a design professional and front-end developer to keep myself occupied and offering my skills where they can of use.

# **Design Lead - Contract** Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

### Vodafone, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Design Lead working with the Content Team, I was accountable for a range of UI design tasks.

#### Responsibilities

# Digital brand update

Enhance portions of the Vodafone NZ public website and execute a digital brand update.

#### Design

Re-design web pages, journeys, components. Ensured brand guidelines are adhered to. Deliverables included design files and components, presented for a range of screen sizing and collaborate with stakeholders.

#### **Templates**

Created template designs and components to be consistent, work independently and together as a whole.

#### Pattern libraries & style guides

Designed, built and managed pattern libraries and style guides for design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

#### **Senior Digital Designer**

2004 - 2018

#### Datacom Systems Limited, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Senior Digital Designer in the Digital Experience Team, I grew and developed indispensable skills. I worked with multiple teams and environments. I was accountable for a range of UI/UX, graphic design tasks and had a hand in front-end development.

#### Responsibilities

#### · Estimating and proposal review

Defined what efforts would be required for delivery. Review project plans and proposals and made suggestions where value could be added.

#### Design

Designer for a range of projects, both restrictive and customer facing. Deliverables included design files, templates and prototypes. Iterative wireframes to clarify screen requirements, elements/components and functionality. Explored flows, scenarios and created design options on analysis.

#### · Pattern libraries & style guides

Designed, built and managed pattern libraries and style guides for design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

# HTML prototypes

Created semantic and accessible HTML/SCSS prototypes and templates.

#### **Projects**

#### · Customer facing websites

At Datacom, I initially worked for Air New Zealand managing their CMS; designing and building homepage and landing page takeovers, updating content, integrating new designs and layouts. Other websites, which have since been updated; Bayleys, NZ Lotteries, Ballance, Spark and Fisher & Paykel Finance. Current websites include the HTML/CSS deliverables and translation to responsive design for Auckland Airports and UI/UX design and HTML/CSS deliverables for Aon Insurance.

#### · Micro-sites and module add-ons

Analysis, flow, wire-frame and design work for Chorus, Spark and Auckland Airports.

#### Web applications

UI/UX design and HTML deliverables for internal Cloud Services and Payroll applications. External application for Australian Red Cross Blood Service for their Organ Management System used by scientists and medical professionals.

#### Customer portals

UI design and HTML deliverables for Kotahi Logistics. A customer portal for container ordering, tracking and management.

#### Intranets

UI design and HTML deliverables for internal intranet for Datacom. UI Design for Bupa Health. Integration with Microsoft CRM and Salesforce.

#### · Graphic design

Create and manage print material for internal projects, prepared and composed collateral for internal and external research, analysis and sales presentations.

#### · Internal innovation hackfests

I participated in annual internal innovation hackfests. Made myself available as a design resource and mentorship of graduates.

#### **Achievements**

- I introduced HTML pattern libraries to assist integration teams implementing consistent components.
- · Delivery of accessible and functional HTML templates and prototypes for integration teams and

# Web & Print Designer 2001 - 2003

# London Centre of Contemporary Music, London, United Kingdom

The LCCM and the London College of Creative Media employed me to design their website. I also worked with their integration team to build their Student Management System. Other tasks I took on; design their identity logo, produce various print materials, course brochures, posters and stationery.

#### **Designer**

1996 - 2001

#### Contract UI Designer, London, United Kingdom

I worked for various design agencies across London in a variety of roles including; UI design for interactive TV, designer hand for Air New Zealand livery and British Telecom, where I was employed to design the UI for a child safe web browser.

# **Designer** 1993 - 1996

Designer, Megabyte/Terabyte, Auckland

Multimedia designer on a range of interactive projects.

# **Education**

**Web Accessibility** 

**Deque University** 

2021 - Present day

Received scholarship to participate in online digital accessibility courses.

Introduction to digital

accessibility

2020

**Victoria University** 

Exploring digital accessibility and what it takes to ensure online content is accessible.

Graded: A-

**Diploma of Computer** 

**Graphic Design** 

1992 - 1994

Whanganui School of Design, Whanganui, New Zealand

Three year Diploma of Computer Graphic Design.

Delivery of an interactive design and typography project for final year.

# **Interests**

Outside of my professional interests, caring for my children keeps me busy as a sole parent. I also muck in garden, make chili jam, play the guitar and DIY stuff.

Cook more vegetarian food and grow more chilies.

